timetrade.com 2019-03-28

# Privacy Statement | TimeTrade

TimeTrade Systems, Inc. (“ **TimeTrade** ”) respects your privacy and values your trust. We are committed to ensuring that the personal information stored by our systems is suitably protected and used appropriately. This Privacy Statement describes the treatment and handling of any personal information collected by the TimeTrade website at [www.timetrade.com](https://www.timetrade.com/), including all related pages and landing pages, and/or by the use of TimeTrade’s services, including:

  * What personally identifiable information is collected;
  * How TimeTrade may use the personally identifiable information and with whom and when this information may be shared with third parties;
  * Your rights to your personal information and how you can submit a request to view, remove, change, or transfer the collected personal information; and
  * To whom questions regarding this Privacy Statement should be directed.

By using this website, you agree to comply with and be bound by this Privacy Statement and the Terms and Conditions of Use published at www.timetrade.com/terms-and-conditions-use. This Privacy Statement is incorporated into those Terms, and capitalized terms used, but not defined herein, have the meanings ascribed to them in the Terms.

 **PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT CAREFULLY, AND PLEASE CHECK THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT FREQUENTLY, AS TIMETRADE RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT AT ANY TIME WITHOUT NOTICE. BY ACCESSING THIS WEBSITE OR THE SERVICES AFTER THE “LAST UPDATED” DATE SET FORTH BELOW, YOU ARE DEEMED TO CONSENT TO OUR THEN-CURRENT PRIVACY STATEMENT.**

 **1\. Definitions**   
“SMB” refers to TimeTrade’s Personal, Professional, Workgroup, Individual, or Business Edition SaaS offerings. These offerings are for individuals and businesses or groups that require one-to-one appointment scheduling functionality or appointment routing. The SMB service is owned and operated by TimeTrade and sold on a per Subscriber basis. Terms of use for the SMB SaaS offering are detailed [here](https://www.timetrade.com/smb-terms-of-service/).

“ **Scheduler for Enterprise** ” refers to TimeTrade’s SaaS product offering for larger businesses or organizations that require high volume scheduling, configurable interfaces and complex business rules. Scheduler for Enterprise is licensed under the terms and conditions set forth in our agreement with our Subscriber.

“ **Subscriber** ” is a single customer of the services provided by TimeTrade.

“ **User** ” is any person or device that connects to services hosted by TimeTrade.

“ **Visitor** ” is any person or device that connects to this website.

 **2\. Use of Information Gathered by TimeTrade During Registration For Services or Other General Inquiries.**   
When you visit TimeTrade’s website for information regarding our products, promotions, employment opportunities or to register to use TimeTrade’s services, TimeTrade may gather information about you such as your name, business type, contact information, email address, payment method, and billing address information. If you disclose any personal data to us, you consent to our processing and use of such personal data in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Information may be used to: a) contact you directly regarding TimeTrade services, career opportunities and/or to respond to your inquiries; or b) provide invoicing of the subscribed services.

Unless permission is provided through our Opt-in process, we will not sell or rent your personal information to any third party or use your e-mail address for unsolicited mail. Any emails sent by TimeTrade will only be in connection with the provision of agreed services, products or inquiries.

 **3\. Sharing of Collected Information, “Opt-in”**   
The SMB product offering provides an “opt-in” option for Subscribers and their associated Users to receive further information from TimeTrade and third parties. If the User or Subscriber opts-in, TimeTrade may share names and email addresses with selected partners so that such partners may contact them with offers that may be of interest to them. Users and Subscribers can opt-out of receiving such information at any time by unsubscribing to the marketing emails via the unsubscribe links presented in the email. Scheduler for Enterprise Subscriber data is not used or included in any TimeTrade or third party marketing programs.

 **4\. Credit Card Transactions**   
Online credit card payments related to SMB subscriptions are processed by a PCI certified payment processing vendor utilizing secure, encrypted payment card processing methods. Financial information will not be shared with any party not directly involved with billing of the services.

 **5\. Use of Information**   
The functionality of the TimeTrade services allows Subscribers to collect information from a User for the scheduling of an appointment with the Subscriber. As a function of the services, Subscribers may customize the data that is collected from Users. Typically, the data collected is: First & Last Name, Email Address and Telephone number. Pursuant to best practices and privacy regulations, Subscribers should limit the amount of personally identifiable information collected to only that which is strictly necessary. A Subscriber should never ask for, and a User should never provide, sensitive information such as a credit card number or government identification number via the TimeTrade services.

Except as specified elsewhere in this Policy Statement, TimeTrade considers all User information collected by TimeTrade on behalf of a Subscriber to be the proprietary information of the applicable Subscriber. Accordingly, all User personal information is controlled by the Subscriber and is subject to the Subscriber’s privacy policy and practices, which may differ from this policy.

TimeTrade will retain the information collected by our Subscribers until the User or Subscriber requests its removal or the Subscriber terminates its relationship with TimeTrade. In either case TimeTrade will modify the collected data to be unreadable and unrecoverable. TimeTrade employees may periodically access Subscriber data solely for administrative purposes, application support, or to improve systems efficiency and add enhancements.

TimeTrade uses third-party service providers who work on our behalf and who are bound by contract to keep all information confidential and use the information solely to carry out the services that they are performing for us. For example, TimeTrade uses third party service providers to assist with the following: Hosting of the application servers and collected data and sending appointment confirmations, reminder e-mails and text/SMS messages.

If required by law, TimeTrade may access or disclose information collected by our systems on behalf of a Subscriber, to appropriate authorities. Unless otherwise prohibited, a disclosure request shall be promptly communicated to the Subscriber, i.e. data owner.

 **6\. Scheduling & Appointment Confidentiality**   
TimeTrade internally classifies all scheduling and appointment information as confidential and proprietary to the Subscriber. TimeTrade will never share a Subscriber’s schedule or appointment data with any third party outside the scope of TimeTrade’s services.

For user experience, analytical and support purposes, TimeTrade may record Subscriber User session-specific information, such as source IP, accessing browser and which pages or functions within the application were accessed. For Users scheduling appointments with a Subscriber, TimeTrade will not share their scheduling information with anyone except the Subscriber with whom they are making an appointment. A Subscriber can only view information relating to their instance of services.

 **7\. Links to Other Websites**   
Other websites and applications not under the direct control of TimeTrade are not governed by this Privacy Statement. Emails generated by Subscribers as part of the TimeTrade services may contain links to enable Users to visit other websites. Be aware that TimeTrade does not have any control over the target website and cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information that a User provides while visiting them. Caution should be exercised when visiting unknown websites, and the privacy statement applicable to the website in question should be reviewed prior to use.

 **8\. Children**   
Children should request permission from their parent or guardian prior to sending personal information online. TimeTrade does not intentionally collect any personal information from individuals under the age of 13. No part of TimeTrade’s website is structured to attract anyone under the age of 13. If a child has provided TimeTrade or a TimeTrade Subscriber with personal information via the websites or services and the parent or guardian would like this information removed from the Subscriber’s data, the parent or guardian of that child should contact the Subscriber and ask that the data be removed from their records. If further assistance is needed, contact TimeTrade directly at [privacy@timetrade.com](mailto:privacy@timetrade.com) and we will use reasonable efforts to assist in the deletion of the child’s personal information.

 **9\. Information Automatically Collected**   
TimeTrade collects information about the systems that connect to our website and services. Examples of this type of information include the IP address and type of Internet Browser and/or computer operating system used in the connection, and/or the domain name of the website and/or Internet Service Provider linked to our website or services. In addition, TimeTrade may collect general usage statistics and provide them to prospective advertisers or partners. This information is collected in aggregate form and does not include any personal information about specific Users, Subscribers or Visitors.

 **10\. Mobile Applications and Devices**   
TimeTrade services are accessible via any supported internet connected web browser. This Privacy Statement is applicable to all Subscribers, Users and Visitors connected via a supported mobile device browser.

 **11\. Internet Browser Cookies**   
When any web browser connects to a TimeTrade provided website or service, the websites and services utilize browser cookies to a) provide a customizable and personalized experience, such as personal site preferences; b) record User session-specific information, such as which pages within the application were accessed; c) provide application session control to the servers hosting the application; and d) determine the device/browser type being used and its approximate geo-location. Disabling the support of browser cookies is not recommended: non-use of cookies may lead to reduced functionality and or an unsatisfactory user experience.

 **12\. Security**   
TimeTrade’s websites and services have reasonable administrative, technical, and physical safeguards in place designed to protect your personal information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alternation, or destruction. TimeTrade utilizes industry adopted server and database security measures, including encryption of personal data over public networks. TimeTrade also limits its employee’s access to personal information. Despite these protections, no information system is 100% secure, so we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your information at all times.

 **13\. Privacy Shield, Rights of EU Data Subjects & International Data Transfers from the European Economic Area (EEA)**   
TimeTrade Systems Inc. complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework(s) (Privacy Shield) as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and the United Kingdom and/or Switzerland to the United States in reliance on Privacy Shield. TimeTrade Systems Inc. has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles with respect to such information. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/)

TimeTrade respects an EEA individual’s rights to access personal information about them, and to limit use and disclosure of their personal information. TimeTrade has limited ability to access information our customers submit to our services, however, if you wish to request access, to limit use, or to limit disclosure, please provide the name of the TimeTrade customer who submitted your personal information to our services. We will refer your request to that customer and will support them as needed in responding to your request.

TimeTrade is accountable for personal information that it receives and subsequently transfers to third parties. If third parties that process personal information on our behalf do so in a manner that does not comply with the Privacy Shield Principles, we are accountable, unless we prove that we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

Individuals in the EEA may submit inquiries or complaints related to our processing of personal information under the Privacy Shield Framework directly to us at the e-mail address listed below in Section 16. In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, TimeTrade maintains an independent mechanism to investigate unresolved Privacy Shield complaints regarding our compliance to the Privacy Shield Principles. If we have not been able to successfully resolve your inquiry or complaint and you are based in the EU, you may raise your inquiry or complaint to JAMS ADR at [www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield](https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield). The services of JAMS are provided at no cost to you. In addition, as further explained in the Privacy Shield Principles, a binding arbitration option will also be made available to you in order to address residual complaints not resolved by any other means.

TimeTrade privacy practices are subject to the jurisdiction of the United States Federal Trade Commission (FTC) and as such TimeTrade is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the FTC.

 **14\. Requests to View, Remove, Change, or Transfer Your Personal Information Collected by TimeTrade**   
To view, remove, change, or transfer the personal information collected by this website, please send a written request detailing your desired action to privacy@timetrade.com, or you may send the request to:

Data Privacy & Compliance   
TimeTrade Systems Inc   
100 Ames Pond Drive STE100   
Tewksbury MA 01876

 **15\. Requests to View, Remove, Change, or Transfer Your Personal Information Collected By a Subscriber.**   
As noted above, TimeTrade considers all User information collected by TimeTrade on behalf of a Subscriber to our services, to be the proprietary information of the applicable Subscriber. A Subscriber, may share your information pursuant to their own privacy policies. To initiate a request to modify the collected information from a Subscriber’s data set, you must contact the Subscriber (the company you booked an appointment with, via the TimeTrade services) and request the desired action. The Subscriber should have provided you with the appropriate contact information during the appointment booking process. If you are unable to resolve your request with the Subscriber, please provide the name of the TimeTrade customer who submitted your personal information to our services. We will refer your request to that customer and will support them as needed in responding to your request.

 **16\. Contacting Us**   
Please direct any questions regarding our Privacy Statement to our privacy coordinator at [privacy@timetrade.com](mailto:privacy@timetrade.com).

 _This document was last updated on 02/13/2019._
